cree.com 2017-12-02

# Privacy Policy | Cree, Inc.

This Privacy Policy tells you what kinds of information we collect about you when you visit our website, communicate with us, or make a purchase from us, and how we use and share that information. By using our website or other Cree services, you accept the policies and practices that we have described in this Privacy Policy. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, by posting updates to our website. An update will be effective for any website use after the date of the update. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time for possible changes. Your use of our website or services after an update constitutes your agreement to the update. In this Privacy Policy, the words “Cree”, “we”, “us”, and “our” refer to Cree, Inc. and its subsidiaries.

Our websites are controlled and operated within the United States of America. CREE MAKES NO REPRESENTATION THAT OUR WEBSITE IS APPROPRIATE FOR USE BY CONSUMERS OUTSIDE THE UNITED STATES.

**What Does This Privacy Policy Apply To?**

****This Privacy Policy applies to our websites which reference it, and our mobile applications, social media sites, and other electronic communications we may have with you. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected by our subsidiary E-conolight through its websites or otherwise.  This Privacy Policy also does not apply to any website(s) owned and operated by suppliers, manufacturers, distributors, advertisers or other third parties.

**What Information Do We Collect?**

****Our information collection includes information obtained through our website, mobile applications, social media, other electronic and offline communications.  

Cree collects information about you in three different ways. The first is when you voluntarily provide information to us. The second is through automatic collection of traffic and other information about visitors to our website. The third is when we receive information from third parties that collect and provide information to businesses like Cree to help us provide better products and services. 

Information that you voluntarily provide to us

You can read about Cree and our products on our website without sharing your name and contact information. 

In certain places on this website, you may be asked to provide your name, contact information and/or email address to use a website feature or communicate with us. Opening an account may require information, for example your name, company, email address, telephone number, mailing address, and credit card numbers. It is your option to provide the information requested. To place an order, we may ask you for financial information such as a credit card number, billing and shipping addresses. 

Cree may retain records of any messages which you may send to us through this website or other websites owned by Cree, or by other electronic communications with Cree.

We may collect information when you provide product reviews, post online questions or submit information to us. We may choose to share your comments through our marketing campaigns and communications. Please see our [Terms of Use](http://www.cree.com/legal/terms-of-use/) for more information regarding submitting information to Cree.

Information collected automatically 

__When you visit our website, our information technology systems automatically collect information about the equipment you are using and about your use of our website and services. Examples of the information we collect and analyze include the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, the login name and password for the website if you sign in for access, the email address which you use to communicate with us, your computer and connection information (for example, browser type, version, and time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system, and platform), and records of your purchases with us. We also may collect URL click stream information to, through, and from our websites, which shows your website navigation history. This information may include the date and time of your visit, cookie number, if any, and products you viewed or searched for. We may also use browser data such as cookies for fraud prevention and other purposes. We may use software tools to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (for example scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page. We may also collect technical information to help us identify your device for fraud prevention and for dealing with diagnostic purposes relating to our website.

Other information we might collect

We may also receive personal information about you from third parties, including contact information, user information, address and shipping information and credit information.

**How We Use Information We Collect**

Cree does not disclose personally identifiable information collected from you during visits to this website except as provided in this Privacy Policy. Cree may aggregate collected information from multiple customers and visitors to create data which can be analyzed to determine general customer and visitor levels of interest in particular products or services. We may also analyze collected URL click stream information to, through, and from our websites.  Information may be shared among Cree, Inc. and its subsidiaries, agents, distributors and resellers and with third parties which Cree has engaged for purposes of improving our products and services, informing you about Cree products or services, and providing products or services to you. We may use your personal information to improve our services, to customize the content you see, and for research, marketing and other business purposes. We may also contact you from time to time to inform you of our products and services and to ask for comments.  

We may work with online advertising companies to provide you with advertising which is tailored to your interests. These ads may be seen on our website, other Cree websites or on other third-party sites which you visit. These ads may be based on information gathered as you browsed our website or based on your transactions with us. Our advertising partners collect information using cookies, web beacons, and other technologies which do not identify you personally. For more information about interest-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used for interest-based advertising, please visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). 

Cree may share your information with third party service providers for processing payments made by credit or debit card in connection with fulfilling and delivering ordered products or other material. Cree also may disclose your information if Cree has a good faith belief that the disclosure is required by law, is required in order to enforce the [Terms of Use](http://www.cree.com/legal/terms-of-use/) for this website, or is necessary to detect, prevent or address fraud or security issues or to prevent harm to Cree or others. Cree may transfer your information to companies that purchase lines of business from Cree that have been displayed our websites.

**Third-Party Services**

This website may offer features and services which are administered or provided by third parties hired by Cree. To receive these services, you may be required to provide these third parties with personal information. This website may also contain links to other sites which are not owned, maintained, operated or endorsed by or for Cree. Since such services and sites are subject to separate privacy practices and security protocols established by the third-party providers, please read the other sites’ privacy policies to understand how your personal information is collected, used and protected when you visit those sites.  Otherwise, Cree does not authorize third parties to collect and use personally identifiable information from or through our website except for the purpose of providing services to or on behalf of Cree.

**How We Use Cookies**

Depending upon the settings of your browser, Cree may make use of cookies or other technology to store information about you and your visits to this website on your equipment so that Cree’s systems can recognize you and provide you information more efficiently the next time you visit our website. 

Cookies enhance our ability to provide you information and services. Cookies are pieces of text that a website stores on your computer that can be accessed by the website when you return to the site. Cookies help us improve your experience since they recall your use of the Internet and our website and services, your preferences, and your login and password to our website.

We are aware that not everyone wants to permit the use of cookies. If you do not want to enable cookies, the help feature on most browsers will tell you how to change your browser settings to manage cookies.

**How We Protect Information**

Our site uses industry-standard encryption technology to provide for the security of your credit card numbers, security codes and expiration dates. We also have reasonable procedural and technical standards to protect the security of our site and the information we maintain. We cannot guarantee, however, that any electronic commerce or communication is totally secure.

**Removing or Updating Personal Information**

If you believe your personal information is not accurate, or if you would like us to delete personal information collected by Cree, please contact us at [webmaster@cree.com](mailto:webmaster@cree.com).

**Email**

Recipients of our email marketing messages can unsubscribe from receiving promotional email by using the unsubscribe instructions located in the bottom of the message.

**Children’s Information**

Cree does not seek information from persons less than 13 years of age, and no information should be submitted to this website by visitors less than 13 years of age.

**Users Outside the United States**

The website is managed from and operated in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States, and by using the website or providing your information, you consent to this transfer, and understand that the United States may not provide the same level of protection for your personal information as the laws of your country.
